Good morning and welcome again to Your City Today.
With me today is Graham Campbell, a councillor from the city council.
He will be telling us about the plan to improve the fast-growing suburb of
Red Hill.
Good morning Graham and welcome to the show.
Good morning, Carol.
Now, Graham, I understand that there has been a lot of community consultation for
the new plan?
Yes, we've tried to address some of the concerns that local groups told us
about.
People we've heard from are mainly worried about traffic in the area,
and, in particular, the increasing speed of cars near schools.
They feel that it is only a matter of time before there is an
accident as a lot of the children walk to the school.
So we're trying to do something about that.
Another area of concern is the overhead power lines.
These are very old and a lot of people we spoke to asked if
something could be done about them.
Well, I'm happy to report that the power company have agreed to move the
power lines underground at a cost of $800,000.
I think that will really improve the look of the area, as well as
being safer.
That's good to know,
but will that mean an increase in rates for the local businesses in that
area?
Well, the power company have agreed to bear the cost of this themselves after
a lot of discussion with the council.
This is wonderful news as the council now has some extra funds for us
to put into other things like tree planting and art work.
Now, we've also put together a map which we've sent out to all the
residents in the area.
And on the map we've marked the proposed changes.
Firstly, we'll plant mature pine trees to provide shelter and shade just to the
right of the supermarket in Days Road.
In order to address the traffic problems, the pavements on the corner of Carberry
and Thomas Street be widened.
This will help to reduce the speed of vehicles entering Thomas Street.
We think it's very important to separate the local residential streets form the main
road.
So the roadway at the entry of Thomas Street from Days Road will be
painted red.
This should mark it more clearly and act as a signal for traffic to
slow down.
One way of making sure that the pedestrians are safe is to increase signage
at the intersections.
A 'keep clear' sign will be erected at the junction of Evelyn Street
and Hill Street, to enable traffic to exit at all times.
Something we're planning to do to help control the flow of traffic in the
area is to install traffic lights half way down Hill Street where it crosses
Days Road.
Now, we haven't only thought about the cars and traffic, of course, there's also
something for the children.
We're going to get school children in the area to research a local story,
the life of a local sports hero perhaps,and an artist will incorporate that story
into paintings on the wall of a building on the other side of Hill
Street from the supermarket.
And finally, we've agreed to build a new children's playground which will be at
the other end of Hill Street close to the intersection with Carberry Street.
Wonderful, now, what's the next stage?
Well, the final plan...